

G. SUJANA RUKYA

DATA SCIENTIST AND ENGINEER IN ELECTRICAL AND ELECTRONICS | HTTPS://WWW.LINKEDIN.COM/IN/SUJANA-RUKYA-A0AB47230

OBJECTIVE

Team-oriented and creative data scientist with two years of experience in database management and statistical analysis. Qualified graduate with a bachelor's degree in Electrical and Electronics with certification in Advanced Data Science and AI, offering expertise in statistical modeling, data mining and extraction.

Significant background in Python and SQL coding, Advanced Excel and MS Office.

SKILLS

Hard Skills

- Data modelling
- Machine Learning
- Statistical Analysis
- Data Mining
- Predictive modelling
- Database Management

EXPERIENCE

MACHINE LEARNING INTERN • SUVIDHA FOUNDATION • FEB 2023 – MARCH 2023

PROJECT NAME: Applying Transform -Based Text Summarization for Key phrase Generation.
Coding Platform: Google Colab

TECHNICAL TRAINOR • ST PAUL CONVENT • FEB 2017 – JUNE 2018 Trained Students In C, C++, Java, Cloud Computing And Artificial Intelligence.

TECHNICAL TRAINOR • AIR FORCE SCHOOL • SEP 2020 – JAN 2023 Trained Students In Data Base Management System, Advanced Excel And MS Office.

Worked with the projects in Atal Lab using Arduino and Python. Designed the School Website with WordPress Edited the website content and School Magazine.

EDUCATION

BE - ELECTRICAL AND ELECTRONICS • 2012 • ANNA UNIVERSITY CHENNAI - FRANCIS XAVIER COLLEGE OF ENGINEERING CGPA - 7.6

Project: Contra Rotating Generator

B.ED • 2019 • MDU UNIVERSITY Percentage – 82%

Techniques

- Probability
- Artificial Intelligence
- Data Visualization
- Worked on ATAL Lab Projects based on Arduino and Python coding

Tools and software

- SOL
- Tableau
- MATLAB
- R

Languages

- Tamil (Native)
- Hindi
- English

CERTIFICATION

Advanced Certification In Data Science And AI – INDIAN INSTITUTE OF TECHNOLOGY – MADRAS (IIT – MADRAS) – INTELLIPAAT (JAN 2023 – JUNE 2023) PRESENT

PROJECTS

EXPLORATORY DATA ANALYSIS (EDA) WITH PYTHON AND PANDAS.

- 1. Ask lot of questions about the data.
- 2. Discover the underlying structure of the data.
- 3. Test hypothesis and validate assumptions about the data.
- 4. Think about what problems you could potentially solve with the data.

WORD FREQUENCY IN CLASSIC NOVELS

Web Scraping using Python – Scraping and cleaning the text data using NLP to find the most frequent words in Moby Dick.







